Inventory of the Corporación Observatorio para la Paz collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Corporación Observatorio para la Paz collection
1974-1981
2001C68
3 manuscript boxes. (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Videotape cassettes, and photocopies of memoranda, clippings, and pamphlets, relating to guerrilla movements in Colombia, and especially to the Movimiento 19 de Abril. Collected by the Corporación Observatorio para la Paz.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2001.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
The guerrilla movement in Colombia started in 1964 as a means to represent the rural poor in a struggle against Colombia's wealthier classes. The Movimiento 19 de April was a guerrilla movement that began in 1970 and was active until 1990. The FARC (Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia) was at the center of guerrilla warfare in Colombia, leading the movement. Opposition to the influence of the United States in Colombia was a main concern. The Corporación Observatorio para la Paz was a group dedicated to addressing issues related to peace, conflict, violence, democracy, security, and disarmament in Colombia.
Scope and Content of Collection
Videotape cassettes, and photocopies of memoranda, clippings, and pamphlets, relating to guerrilla movements in Colombia, and especially to the Movimiento 19 de Abril. Collected by the Corporación Observatorio para la Paz.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Corporación Observatorio para la Paz.; Guerrillas--Colombia.; M-19 (Colombian guerrilla group); Videotapes
Collection Contents
- Movimiento 19 de April file, 1974-1981. (Box 1)
  Contains articles, letters, documents and reports concerning the Movimiento 19 de April. Also included are 8 VHS videotape cassettes.
  - 1974 (Folder 1: 1)
  - 1977 (Folder 1: 2-3)
  - 1978 (Folder 1: 4)
  - 1979 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Video index, 1974-1981 (Folder 1: 6)
- Guerrilla movement file, 1974-1979. (Box 2)
  Contains articles (mainly from newspapers), excerpts from books, and reports regarding the guerrilla movement in Colombia.
  - 1974 (Folder : 1)
  - 1975 (Folder : 2)
  - 1976 (Folder : 3)
  - 1977 (Folder : 4)
  - 1978 (Folder : 5)
  - 1979 (Folder : 6)
- Articles, 1980-1981. (Box 3)
  Articles from newspapers and magazines, conference reports, and letters discussing the current events in Colombia.
  - 1980 (Folder 3: 1-2)
  - 1981 (Folder 3: 3)